<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>MVLRGraph</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        This node provides a 3D representation to obtain a visual "closeness of fit" test when provided a co-efficients table output by an upstream multivariate regression node.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>The node is intended as a visual aid to check model fit or prevent overfitting. It also serves as a good presentation tool and generally improves
        basic understanding of relationships between columns/variables in a data set. This node can visualize linear and polynomial regression models between 2 and 9 degrees. &#xD; &#xD; &#xA;</intro><intro> While it is only
        possible to represent three dimensions in 3D space (x,y,z); this node can make assumptions about other variables to help visualize a model. Currently, this node uses real data values
        for each point plotted on the 3D plane and, in the model plane, uses the arithmetic mean for variables that are not represented on the x, y, or z plane. 
        </intro>
        
                <tab name="General Options">
        <option name="Target Column">Select the target column used in the Regression Learner Node (z-axis): </option>
        <option name="Select the two independent variables to model(Column Selection)">In the column selection windows, manipulate the names of the data columns until you have exactly two remaining
        in the right hand container. These will be used as the independent variables when modeling the learned regression equation. The two columns will
        be represented visually as the "x" and "y" axis variables on the 3D graph. &#xD; &#xD; &#xA; </option><option> IMPORTANT: these columns must have been used as variables in the previous
        regression node. If you select a column that is in the data column, but is NOT in the coefficients table, then the node will intentially fail when
        executing. If the node fails, check your selected columns in the right hand side to make sure they match the columns used in your regression node.
        </option>
        <option name="Append Column">This option allows you to append a column containing the calculated value of a row, using the regression equation from the 
        the previous node.
        </option>
        <option name="Plot All Real Data Points">Select this option if you want a point on the graph for each row in the data table. If this option is selected
        you cannot define a specific number of points to display in the next option.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of data points to plot">If you do not want all data points to be represented in the graph, you may define a specific number of
        points to display. These points will be chosen sequentially from the top of the data table moving down.
        </option>
        <option name="Display Regression Model">This option allows you to toggle the display of the modeled 3D plane representation of the previous node,
        essentially leaving a 3D scatter plot of the data points.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Regression Co-efficients Table">Takes in the output coefficient table produced by a regression node (linear/polynomial).</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Source Data Table">Takes in the data corresponding to the regression function produced in the regression node. Columns must match the output coeffiecients columns. Can either take the training data table (which was porocessed by the regression node) or the test data (for a visual representation of function "fitness").</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Out-Port name">Outputs the input data table (not the coefficient table).</outPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="3D Regression Plot">3-Dimensional Representation of real data points mapped over a planar model of a learned regression equation.</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
